Abel Misiocha

Nairobi County, Kenya



abel@abeldev.site



linkedin.com/in/devabel



+254794111373



https://abeldev.site

Summary

Solution-driven Junior Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer focused websites using TypeScript, React, Node.js and JavaScript. Built products meeting the standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Experience



FREELANCE FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

H-educate

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023 (4 months)

- Estimated work hours and tracked progress using Scrum methodology.
- Analyzed work to generate logic for new systems, procedures and tests.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Used NodeJS, ORM and SQL/No-SQL to develop and manage databases.
- Created interactive User Interfaces to improve user experience.
- Tuned systems to achieve optimal performance.



Intern

Joseck Consultancy

Feb 2022 - May 2022 (4 months)

- Analyzed problems and worked with a team to develop solutions.
- Explored new technologies and approaches to streamline processes.
- Conducted extensive research for startup company projects.
- Collaborated with senior management on new initiatives to build confidence.

Education



Lux-Tech Academy

React BootCamp, Computer Software Engineering 2022 - 2022

Attended Lux Tech Academy's React bootcamp to deepen my knowledge and skills in ReactJS, a popular JavaScript library for building dynamic web applications. With prior experience in React, I found the program to be an excellent opportunity to advance my understanding of more advanced topics such as Redux, React Router, and Hooks. Through the bootcamp, I gained hands-on experience working on complex projects and received guidance from experienced instructors to help me improve my skills. Overall, the program was an enriching experience that helped me solidify my React knowledge and prepare for more challenging roles in front-end web development.

Holberton School

Computer Software Engineering
Jun 2022 - Jun 2023
Full-stack web development

Skills

Node.js • React.js • JavaScript • TypeScript • Next.js • Tailwind CSS • MongoDB • Express.js • Git • Postman API